Think you could hide
from me, did you?
Did you read what it said?
It said, "Found you!"
- It means I tickle...
- Samuel.
Bee.
That's enough.
You don't want to get overheated.
- I'm not.
- You sure?
Good. Because now it's my turn!
Dad, help!
You need help?
Oh, sure, I can help tickle you.
I think the bottom of these feet
might be very ticklish.
Time for bed, Bee.
Thank you.
Mmm...
Love you, Mommy.
Love you more.
Mommy?
Just for a little while.
Thanks.
You are my sunshine
My only sunshine
You make me happy
when skies are gray
- Mommy?
- Mmm-hmm?
Can we play dollies when we get home?
Well, I think if you help me
with the washing up,
I could play dollies with you
all afternoon.
- Sam!
- Yes!
Sam!
Morning, Sam.
- Morning, Esther.
- Morning.
Hey, there, busy Bee.
Sam, just wondering if you got
that order of mine ready yet.
I got customers coming into my store
every day, asking about your dolls.
You can send your son over tomorrow, Vic.
They're ready.
Well, hallelujah.
I guess prayers do get
answered, don't they?
They do.
All right, well, thank you so much.
Y'all have a good Sunday.
- You have a good day, too.
- You have a lovely day.
In you get.
Damn it!
Language.
There's a car coming.
Why don't I wave it down
and see if we can get some help?
No, no, no. I got it.
I'll get it!
No!
B-L-U-E.
Okay, pick a number.
Linda?
Um...
- Four.
- Okay.
"You will soon make new friends."
Do mine now.
What's wrong?
I just wish you and me were going
to a new home instead of a new orphanage.
Sweet Sue does, too.
It'd be nice to have a home.
Yeah, but only if you're there.
I don't wanna go anywhere you're not.
So let's swear.
If someone wants one of us,
they get both of us.
Okay. I swear.
Good.
Me, too.
You know what I like most about Sweet Sue?
What?
She looks just like you.
So how much further is it, Father?
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph,
you're worse than the children, Sister.
The Mullins agreeing to take us in
was a gift from God.
Yeah.
What kind of person isn't excited
about getting a gift?
I should mention, don't be alarmed if you
don't see much of Mrs. Mullins at first.
She has a condition, you see.
She was in an accident years ago.
You girls would do well
to help her if need be.
It's big.
Janice,
you need help?
No, thanks. I can manage.
Sister.
She's one of the unfortunate ones
with that polio outbreak,
but she's getting stronger every day.
She won't be a burden. I promise you.
Mmm-hmm.
Mr. Mullins, why don't you
show the girls around?
I can unload their belongings.
I'll start inside.
Thank you, Father.
Whoa! This is as big as a castle.
Which obviously makes us the princesses.
If this is our new orphanage, I think
I'm just fine with never being adopted.
There's a TV.
The television no longer works.
The radio, however, does.
This goes on forever.
You're right. We're gonna need a map
to find our way around.
Girls, this way.
As you can see, the dining room is more
than adequate to accommodate all of us.
Look in here.
Let's stay together.
Mrs. Mullins and I stay in here.
Feel free to use the rest
of the downstairs as you see fit.
Your rooms are upstairs.
Mr. Mullins,
is there some way Janice and I
could maybe stay down here?
Me, too.
I'll be fine.
I installed it years ago for my wife.
Hasn't been used in ages.
But it works fine.
Try it, Jan.
If you don't, I will.
Up is up. Down is down.
But it won't work
unless you click the seat belt in,
like this.
Simple.
Thank you.
I got dibs on next!
Wow, nice.
I guess this is ours.
Let's take that side.
Kate and Tierney can have these.
What about Linda and me?
Relax, Janice. This is a big house.
There are other bedrooms.
Why can't Linda and me
have those beds over there?
Okay. But then where
would Kate and Tierney sleep?
Wow.
This is neat.
Locked,
and it stays that way, too.
Hey, Jan.
In here.
Hey,
wanna be bunkmates?
- Hey, Sister Charlotte, can we...
- Oh, Lord,
please bless Nancy with the wisdom
to not give people near heart attacks.
Sorry.
What is your emergency?
Can we go exploring?
Help Father Massey
with your things first, and then...
But Mr. Mullins is doing that.
But that doesn't mean you're...
You know how Father Massey is.
We don't wanna get in the way.
- Fine.
- She said, "Okay"!
But look out for one another!
You coming, Jan?
Maybe in a little while.
Well,
maybe I'll stay, too.
Because you feel sorry for me?
Well...
You promised you wouldn't treat me
any differently.
Okay.
See you!
Dear Lord, thank you
for bringing us all together.
Bless this food for our use...
And us to thy service.
Fill our hearts with grateful praise,
and help us give you glory
each day through.
Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.
Amen.
If you'll excuse me.
Carol.
Keep to your own business.
And if I die before I wake,
I pray the Lord my soul to take.
Please, God, help Linda and me find
a good home that keeps us together...
So we can finally be real sisters...
With good, loving parents...
That hate homework as much as we do.
But even if they don't, that's okay, too.
Amen.
"Find me"?
Nancy?
Carol?
Are you guys in here?
Forgive me, Father,
for I am about to sin.
I heard this is where Mr. Mullins
keeps his wife.
Does she really wear a mask?
Yeah, she looked like a doll.
Mrs. Mullins, you down there?
Stop it.
I think he seems nice.
Why don't you go find Janice,
see what she's up to?
Why?
So you can talk about boys?
Well, do you wanna talk about boys?
Gross.
No.
I wanna play a game.
Okay, let's play hide and seek.
You go hide, and we'll come look for you.
Okay.
So are we gonna look for her?
Maybe.
Bless you.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
I asked Mr. Mullins if we could use
this room for our new classroom,
and he graciously agreed.
Would you like to help?
What's wrong?
I have a sin to confess.
Forgive me, Sister Charlotte,
for I have sinned.
- It's been...
- At least two weeks.
At least two weeks
since my last confession.
There's this room upstairs
that we're not supposed to go into.
But you did anyway.
How'd you know?
Because, otherwise,
why would you be telling me about it?
Well, the door was already open.
I don't know how because Mr. Mullins
always keeps it locked.
When I went inside,
there was this little doll,
- and it was really strange in there.
- Janice.
Weird things started to happen.
Janice, listen to yourself.
What do I always say?
A sin is a sin, no matter the context.
More importantly,
you absolutely cannot disobey the Mullins.
We only just got here,
and they're doing a very generous thing
by allowing us to stay with them.
If they decide to no longer have us here,
we'll all be split up.
So next time you're thinking
of breaking a rule,
think of how that could affect
the other girls, first.
Do you understand me?
Yes. I'm sorry, Sister. I wasn't thinking.
It's okay, love.
For your penance, pray one Hail Mary,
and unpack three of these boxes.
What are you guys doing?
Unpacking boxes.
Oh.
This place is so creepy.
What was that?
How dare you!
Oh, Mr. Scarecrow.
Oh.
Found you.
You're not very good at hiding.
Years of neglect have affected
the counterbalance.
There. That should keep the draft down.
Thank you.
That was taken in Romania
at a convent of cloister nuns.
They have little contact
with the outside world,
but I became very close to these three.
That's Sister Maria. That's Sister Anna.
And that's Sister Lucia.
Who's this?
I don't know.
I don't think I even met her.
Is there anything else you need?
No, thank you.
Good night.
Ooh, I like him.
Which one would you marry?
Oh, I don't know.
I guess I'll just have to date all of them
to find out.
I just want his eyebrows.
His eyes.
He's very handsome.
Night time is when Mrs. Mullins
gets her powers.
That's why she's in bed all day,
but at night,
she can go wherever she wants.
She needs to, so she can feed.
And if you look directly at her,
you'll die.
And to get you to look, she'll keep
saying your name over and over
till you can't stand it.
Wait.
Nancy. Nancy.
- Nancy!
- No, Mrs. Mullins. No!
Nancy.
Shh!
Oh...
No.
She's ready to feed.
Carol!
- Carol!
- Stop it.
- We're not supposed to be up.
- Well, you were doing it, too.
Me?
Okay, why isn't he answering her?
- Nancy.
- Don't look at her.
No! No, please, please, please!
Please! No, please. Please.
- Please, God. Please.
- Please.
She's gone.
She's gone. She's gone.
What's going on?
- What on God's Earth?
- Miss Sister Charlotte!
- Mrs. Mullins!
- She was here.
- We heard her.
- In this room.
She was standing right over there.
Who?
Your wife, apparently.
They said she was just in here.
Oh, that's impossible.
My wife hasn't been able
to walk for years.
Girls.
Girls!
Let's go back to our studies, okay?
You okay, Nance?
Did you really see Mrs. Mullins
in your room last night?
Yes. We swear. We were under the covers...
Nancy, stop it.
We just freaked ourselves out last night.
You know that.
Mrs. Mullins?
Sister Charlotte,
Could I trouble you for a glass of water?
Of course.
All of you are more than welcome
to stay as long as you need.
It's good to hear some life again.
We've been cooped up here so long,
I'd forgotten what that sounded like.
What a lovely picture.
She was taken from us
at an early age, unfortunately.
If you could turn away
for a moment, Sister?
Yes, of course.
I'm very sorry to hear
about your daughter.
But we find comfort in knowing
she waits for you in Heaven.
I wish that were true.
The other night, dear,
as I lay sleeping
I dreamed I held you in my arms
But when I woke, dear, I was mistaken
And I hung my head and cried
You are my sunshine
My only sunshine
Oh, my gosh.
You shouldn't be in here.
Well, neither should you.
Whose room is this, anyways?
The Mullins had a daughter.
It was hers.
"Had" one?
I think she died.
And I think that was her
playing the music, too.
Stop trying to scare me.
I'm not. It's the truth.
Then why are we in here?
- We should leave.
- No.
No.
Linda,
what is it?
We shouldn't be in here.
Okay.
I'll leave in a minute.
Well, I'm going.
Who's doing that?
Hi.
You're the Mullins' daughter, aren't you?
What happened to you?
Will you help me?
What do you need?
Your soul!
Charlotte!
Sister Charlotte!
No! No!
How do you feel?
Give her some space.
Girls,
Janice is feeling a little down right now,
so we need to do what we can
to support her.
Time, I think, is all she needs.
She'll walk again though, right?
We'll have to see.
You need sleep.
That's gonna help you with the healing.
I can't stay here, Sister Charlotte.
We can't stay here.
We need to leave.
Leave?
And go where?
There isn't anywhere else for us to go.
I didn't fall down those stairs.
Something threw me.
What do you mean?
You always say that,
even though we can't see God, we can...
We can feel his presence.
Well, in this house,
I feel a different kind of presence.
What kind?
An evil one.
It's coming after me.
Coming after my soul.
Your soul?
Because I'm the weakest.
No, darling.
Listen, the devil preys
on those weak in faith,
not weak of flesh or bone.
You are as strong as any of us, Janice.
Stronger.
You're quiet, Samuel.
I think it was a mistake
to bring the girls here.
Why?
The girl...
The girl that fell.
Maybe she didn't fall.
Maybe...
It was an accident.
That's all it was.
Accidents happen.
It's been quiet for 12 years.
You should try embracing
the presence of the girls
instead of frightening them away.
You'll be better soon.
I don't think so.
Not this time.
But you have to.
Pretty soon, we'll find a new home.
No one's gonna want me now.
I'd just be a burden.
But you swore we'd stick together.
I take it back.
Maybe I won't get adopted.
You will.
You know why?
Because you're special.
You're gonna get adopted
by a nice family somewhere,
and they're gonna spoil you so much.
You're gonna have so many dolls that you
won't even be able to name all of them.
Sure, I can.
Janice one.
Janice two, Janice three.
Linda?
Time for bed.
I wish you'd come upstairs.
I don't wanna sleep alone.
Here.
Take Becca.
This way,
I'll always be with you.
Then you should have Sweet Sue.
Thank you.
Remember, before all of this,
when we used to sneak around
the orphanage at night?
And eat all the chocolate in the pantry?
Father Massey was convinced
that we had mice.
"Oh, Lord.
Please cleanse my soul of all my sins,
- and cleanse our house of these mice!
- These mice!"
No matter what happens,
nothing can erase all of those things
we did together.
Night, Linda.
Good night, Janice.
A little sunlight will do you some good.
I don't think the sunlight can fix
what's wrong with me.
You mustn't give up hope.
Hope is a home unto itself.
Dwell in it, and it will protect
and keep you.
What book of the Bible is that from?
The book of Charlotte.
But that doesn't make it any less so.
Are you okay here?
The sunlight actually feels kind of nice.
I told you.
Too low.
Sister Charlotte?
No! No, no, no!
Stop, please!
Janice!
What's going on?
I couldn't get out.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I'm worried about Janice.
A few nights ago, she wanted to leave.
Why'd she wanna leave?
Probably because this place
is off the wall.
She told me the Mullins' daughter
was coming for her.
The Mullins had a daughter?
She died a long time ago.
So she's seeing ghosts?
Keep your voice down.
I guess.
Well, you guys saw something.
That wasn't a ghost.
Ghosts can only be of dead people.
But how does that explain what you saw?
Unless it really was Mrs. Mullins.
Or something was just trying to scare you.
You guys are doing a good job
of that on your own.
Janice is probably just looking for ways
to justify us treating her differently.
I don't think so.
Of course you don't.
You'll know what
I mean when you're older.
Now go. Get to bed.
What are you waiting for?
Nothing.
You like it?
It's nice.
It's not my finest work.
You seem troubled.
Maybe I can help.
I don't think so.
Talking about the things
that bothers us, sometimes,
it's all the help we need.
Well,
it's Janice.
She's acting funny.
"Acting funny"?
She says
she's seen your daughter.
My daughter
has been dead for a very, very long time.
I know, but, you see,
Janice went into her bedroom.
She what?
She knows she wasn't supposed to,
but she found this doll and...
What doll?
The one in the white dress.
That's impossible.
That doll was hidden away.
She mustn't go near that doll.
Do you understand me?
Janice, I told you not to use that room.
Please don't take
my sunshine away
Stay here.
Mr. Mullins?
Mr. Mullins, are you okay?
Go get ready for bed, girls.
I need to speak to Mrs. Mullins.
Linda, what are you doing?
This doll,
it's hurting Janice,
and it killed Mr. Mullins.
I'm getting rid of it!
Linda, let's go back.
Linda?
No! No!
- What is that?
- Who cares? Run!
Janice. Janice, I got rid of it.
I got rid of the doll.
Janice?
- What's going on?
- Where's Janice?
- I don't know.
- Go find her.
Hurry!
- What's going on?
- No!
No! Get that thing away from me!
It's back. I knew it was back.
What is it?
Evil.
The devil itself.
What are you talking about?
After Samuel and I lost our daughter,
we prayed and promised our devotion
to whatever power would allow us
to speak or see our beloved girl again.
It started small, the contact.
You are my sunshine
My only sunshine
You make me happy...
But it was her, our busy Bee.
We knew it was her.
She wanted permission to move into
the doll so she could be with us forever.
We said yes,
and that's when it became stronger.
Soon, we could actually see her.
Only in fleeting glimpses,
but it was enough.
Our beloved Bee,
our darling.
Annabelle?
Even though I couldn't hold her,
it was comforting
just to have the buzz of activity again.
But we soon realized
it wasn't our Annabelle at all.
Esther?
It was a demonic presence,
and it was using our Annabelle
to manipulate us
into giving it a soul it could inhabit.
It tried to take mine,
but Samuel reached out to the Church.
They saved my soul, but the evil
was still attached to that doll.
So we locked it away
where it could be surrounded
by the word of God.
It was quiet for all these years.
I thought the evil was contained.
We thought helping the girls
could be our penance.
But we ended up giving it
just what it wanted.
You are sunshine
My only sunshine
You make me happy when skies are gray
You'll never know, dear...
Janice.
Please don't take my sunshine away
She can walk.
It's just us, Janice.
Time to cease from sin, Carol.
- Sister Charlotte!
- Look!
- It's Janice. She did this to me.
- Look what she did!
- Carol, call for help.
- Okay.
And stay together.
They're on the way.
Let's get somewhere safe.
What do we do?
We can't just leave her here, can we?
Mrs. Mullins?
Girls!
Let's go. Now!
Forgive me, Sister, for I have sinned.
- Charlotte! Charlotte!
- Let's go!
Linda!
Go, Kate! Get help!
Or you could help me.
The truck!
Come on, come on.
Come in. Close the door! Close the door!
Come on! Go!
- No!
- Why?
Go! Go!
Look.
Okay.
- No!
- Hurry!
- I'm trying!
- It's there!
- It's not moving.
- I'm trying! I'm trying!
Guys!
Guys! Guys!
Wait. Wait.
The scarecrow.
What scarecrow?
What?
- Kate!
- Get out!
The barn! The barn!
Carol.
What?
No! No! No!
Nancy, I can't get the door open.
Is it locked?
Can you get it from your side?
Girls?
Nancy?
No.
No. No, no, no!
Lord, help me.
Lord, help. Help.
Carol, it's me. It's just me.
Come on.
Linda?
No.
Shoot.
No!
Sister Charlotte?
You know what I like most
about Sweet Sue?
She looks just like you.
Oh, my...
Linda?
Where are you, Linda?
Come out and play.
Found you!
You swore that, if I found a home,
you'd come, too.
You know what they say
about breaking a swear.
You go straight to hell.
Janice!
Forgive me.
No!
Let me out!
Go!
- Sister Charlotte!
Anything?
I'm afraid not.
Still no sign of the girl.
But at her age,
how far could she have gone?
Don't worry.
We'll find her.
The house is blessed.
Whatever evil was here is no longer.
But the doll.
It was a conduit for the evil.
That evil has moved on.
Now the doll is just a doll.
So which one of you gets this?
How are you holding up?
I'm okay.
You know, that wasn't Janice back there.
That was
something else.
I know.
Hi, there.
Welcome. Let's go right inside, shall we?
Sure.
She mostly keeps to herself and can be
a bit quiet, but she's a lovely girl.
She's just been through a lot.
I think you will love her.
Hello. There's someone here
to see you, sweetie.
I wanna introduce you
to Mr. and Mrs. Higgins.
And you must be...
Annabelle.
Annabelle?
What a lovely name.
We brought you a present.
I hope you like dolls.
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
What is it?
- You stay here.
- No, no, no! No, wait!
It's all right. It's okay.
It's all right, sweetheart.
I'm just gonna take a quick look.
Call the police.
- Annabelle!
- Hi, Mom.
John?
The other night, dear
As I lay sleeping
I dreamed I held you in my arms
But when I woke, dear, I was mistaken
And I hung my head and cried
You are my sunshine
My only sunshine
You make me happy when skies are gray
You'll never know, dear,
how much I love you
Please don't take my sunshine away
I'll always love you and make you happy
If you will only say the same
But if you leave me and love another
You'll regret it all someday
You are my sunshine
My only sunshine
You make me happy when skies are gray
You'll never know, dear,
how much I love you
Please don't take my sunshine away